# KIRSI **RALKO**

PO Box 2230, Kenora ON P9N 3X8 · (807) 464-0687 kirsiralko@gmail.com · www.kenorafamilylaw.com

#### **SUMMARY**

Litigation lawyer and business owner pursuing new challenges in the tech field. I am seeking a role that allows me to apply what I've learned in university and the last 5 years in the workforce to a job in coding/development.

Skilled in written communication, research, public speaking and logical reasoning.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **JULY 2019 - PRESENT**

#### LAWYER/OWNER, KIRSI RALKO BARRISTER & SOLICITOR

I am currently the owner of a solo practice established July 2019. Primary focus on Family Law, both litigation and non-litigation. Commencing in July 2020, I also resumed handling residential real estate transactions.

# DECEMBER 2018 – PRESENT CITY COUNCILLOR, CITY OF KENORA

Elected as Councillor At Large for the City of Kenora, 2018 to 2022 term.

Boards and Committees related to this role:

- Harbourtown BIZ (Business Improvement Area) Committee Council Representative
- Association of Municipalities of Ontario (AMO) Youth Advisory Council
- Economic Development Commission Council Representative (Alternate)
- Kenora Public Library Board of Directors Council Representative (Alternate)
- Women in Politics in Northwestern Ontario Committee

**APRIL 2014 - JUNE 2019** 

SHEWCHUK, ORMISTON, RICHARDT & JOHNSON LLP

**ASSOCIATE LAWYER,** JUNE 2016 – JUNE 2019

ARTICLING STUDENT, JUNE 2015 - JUNE 2016

**SUMMER STUDENT, APRIL 2014 – AUGUST 2014** 

As a student, I assisted with files of all types including both litigation and solicitor's work. My practice as an associate was primarily focussed on Family and Civil litigation, with some involvement in Real Estate transactions.

# OCTOBER 2017 – OCTOBER 2019 OWNER, 1885 WINE & WHISKY ROOM

Co-owner and President of an Ontario corporation operating in Kenora, ON as 1885 Wine & Whisky Room, a wine/whisky bar and art gallery focussed on showcasing local artists and musicians. Responsible for business finances, payroll, and inventory.

## **EDUCATION**

## **MAY 2021 (ANTICIPATED)**

## **FULL STACK FLEX CERTIFICATE, CARLETON UNIVERSITY**

Anticipating completion in May 2021, program components covered to date include CSS, Javascript, jQuery and Node. Completed project examples:

#### • Cinco De Mayo Party Planner (Group Project)

Responsible for designing UI (using CSS) and programming the local storage function.

Deployed: <a href="https://www.kirsralk.github.io/APIGroupProject">https://www.kirsralk.github.io/APIGroupProject</a>
Repository: <a href="https://www.github.com/kirsralk/APIGroupProject">https://www.github.com/kirsralk/APIGroupProject</a>

#### Weather Dashboard (Solo Project)

Javascript and jQuery based app that uses APIs to search weather forecasts.

Deployed: <a href="https://www.kirsralk.github.io/APIWeatherDashboard">https://www.kirsralk.github.io/APIWeatherDashboard</a>
Repository: <a href="https://www.github.com/APIWeatherDashboard">https://www.github.com/APIWeatherDashboard</a>

#### Work Day Scheduler (Solo Project)

Javascript and jQuery based app that uses local storage to create a schedule.

Deployed: <a href="https://www.kirsralk.github.io/jQuery-API-Calendar">https://www.kirsralk.github.io/jQuery-API-Calendar</a>
Repository: <a href="https://www.github.com/jQuery-API-Calendar">https://www.github.com/jQuery-API-Calendar</a>

#### **SEPTEMBER 2020**

#### **CERTIFICATE IN FAMILY MEDIATION, YORK UNIVERSITY**

 Currently pursuing AccFM designation, I also possess an Online Dispute Resolution certificate for mediation

#### **MAY 2015**

### JURIS DOCTOR, UNIVERSITY OF MANITOBA (ROBSON HALL)

- Joel & Lily Nitikman Entrance Scholarship
- Robson Hall Negotiation Competition Finalist

#### **MAY 2012**

#### HONOURS BACHELOR OF COMMERCE, LAKEHEAD UNIVERSITY

- First Class Standing
- Dual major concentrations in General Managements and Information Systems
- Minor concentration in Finnish Language

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- Languages: CSS, Javascript, jQuery, Node.js
- Applications: VS Code, GitHub, Git Bash, Slack, Zoom (including as meeting Host)